The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Third Episode
Deadly Challenge
Martial Arts Tournament Volume
Well done!
Enough with the training dummies today!
So exhausting...!
Good morning, Prince!
I was watching you.
Take a look at this sword!
Is there something wrong with it?
Yes! Your master is using a real
sword for practice.
It is indeed very strange.
Tell me, since when do they use
real swords for training?
- Well, Grand Duke, you see...
- You are fired!
- Begone!
- At your command!
Prince, for tomorrow I have
organized a grand tournament
Since you are here,
would you like to participate?
The most skilled knights
who tread our lands will participate!
Officer of the guard, announce me!
Damn! This knight
seems really very strong!
People of the castle, make way
for the certain winner of the tournament!
No one will manage to defeat me!
You think so?
Damn it! Ruffians!
Is this how you treat the best
knight you invited?
Even worse!
I disqualify you for incompetence!
Go back to your lands!
My name is Baron! I have come
for the tournament! How dare you?!
Get lost!
- Help! Go away!
- You will be convinced, I hope,
- that I am the strongest!
- It will be difficult to beat him!
This knight has what it takes
to win the tournament.
He will surely also win the challenge
against Sapphire and kill him!
Kill Sapphire?! I must warn him
of the danger he is facing!
Stork friends, I need you!
They will be fights to the death!
Whoever wins will have
to be an exceptional man.
They have come from the furthest
lands!
Much blood will flow!
It will be tough for everyone!
It seems the favorite
will be a certain Baron.
I have a feeling they
won't let children in.
I'll hide in here and
enter with this lady.
He's stealing my lunch!
Little thief!
I've got it!
Guard, I am the knight Baron!
Welcome, knight!
Please, enter!
I will be the only one to come out!
I am the knight Guillon!
I have come to participate
in the tournament!
- And I will win it!
- Well, you are here too!
Look, look!
My dear enemy Baron!
- Do you hope to win?
- The scar you gave me
..cries out for revenge! I can't wait
to run you through with my sword!
The hatred I bear you for the mark
that you left on my face...
..makes me wish for
the very same thing!
I will kill two birds with one stone:
I will send you to hell
and I will win the tournament too!
- Easier said than done!
- And easy to do!
They scare me...
I am Prince Sapphire!
I thank all the knights..
...who have gathered for this tournament.
I will fight you as equals!
Do not be deceived
by my apparent fragility
nor by the fact
that I am only a boy
nor have any qualms about fighting
against a Prince,
because I am much stronger
than I appear.
What is there to laugh about?
Did you see?!
You are very strong
for a boy!
You had better not laugh anymore!
That fool of a Prince
doesn't know how dangerous it is...
...to provoke those knights!
Now, without a doubt, one of them
..can't wait
to tear him to pieces!
I declare open
the Silverland tournament!
Grand Duke Duralumin
will present the competition!
My friends...
What do you want?!
I wish you all the best of luck!
And expressing the thoughts
of the Prince and myself,
I urge you to fight
to the death!
We will immediately begin the tournament
with three elimination rounds!
Those who emerge as victors
will be admitted to the final challenge!
Good luck to you, knights
Go!
The knight missed two shots!
The next contestant
is Prince Sapphire!
Careful, Sapphire!
If you make it to the final contest,
- you will be killed by the knights!
- Opal!
You're the best!
Prince Sapphire
has missed two...
No!
He didn't miss a single shot!
Now they will take him out...
Also qualifying is
the knight Guillon!
The second round,
gentlewomen and noblemen,
consists of the shooting contest
with the crossbow!
The Prince
has hit the target!
The next challenge will consist
of the axe throw!
Wow, he did it!
It's amazing!
- Sapphire!
- Hello, Tink! What happened to you?
You are so dirty
that I have to wash you a bit.
Did you see the tournament?
It went well for me, don't you think?
I don't think you should be
very happy.
Listen, it would be better
if you withdrew.
Do your head and stomach
happen to hurt a bit?
I'm sorry, Tink,
but I feel perfectly fine.
Still, it would be better for you
- Why are you telling me this?
- They will kill you!
I know that Duralumin wants to have me
killed during the race.
And isn't that a good reason
to give it up?
I'll survive, don't worry
I won't let you participate
in the final race!
There are seven knights who have
passed the qualifiers.
They are about to
fight for the final victory.
They will certainly be
strong enough.
Oh, yes! Strong enough
for the Prince!
I am sure that one of them will certainly
end up defeating him, Grand Duke.
But from the first matches we've
seen that Prince Sapphire, too...
...is rather strong,
so we cannot be sure.
Do you see this bag of gold?
The Grand Duke will give it to
whoever eliminates all the opponents.
I have participated in many
tournaments and I have always won.
Then would you be willing
to do a favor for the Grand Duke,
- by killing one of the competitors?
- Of course! And who would that be?
- The boy, Prince Sapphire.
- The Prince?
Here are two bags!
If you kill him, you will have more.
You can give them to me right now,
because I will kill him.
Good! Good luck!
Hey, Baron!
- Sir Baron, you disappoint me.
- And why is that?
Would you kill an opponent
for a bit of vile money?
I am a professional
and I am at the service of whoever pays me!
Mercenaries like you are not
worthy of fighting with knights.
Damn it! Do you want a lesson?
- See you soon, Baron!
- Damned Guillon!
Knights,
here we are at the grand finale!
I warn you that from now on you can
kill your opponent...
.without being punished!
For the first match, on this
side, the knight Mustang,
on this other side, His Highness
Prince Sapphire!
Sapphire, don't go! He will kill you!
Don't worry, Tink!
You'll see I'll make it! Move aside!
Prince, are you fighting without a helmet?
I don't need it!
Presumptuous daredevil!
Come on, Opal! Forward!
You'll fall to the ground at the first impact!
A tough one, eh?
Take that!
Come at me!
You are defeated, Mustang!
I won, Grand Duke!
The next clash will take place
between knights Baron and Hook!
He is certainly dead.
The next challenge will be held
between knights Guillon and Napal!
Voilà!
And this one is dead too
The next fight.
I'm sorry,
the fight has already taken place.
These challenges are truly
to the death.
If you are afraid,
you can withdraw from the tournament.
- I won't back down!
- If you want, feel free to withdraw.
You shouldn't dig your heels in
out of pride.
- But I want to...
- Sapphire, don't fight!
- Shut up, Tink!
- Sapphire, please don't do it!
Sapphire! I didn't come
to watch the tournament...
...because I was too afraid
that something would happen to you.
Please, be satisfied
with having already won the other contests.
- Withdraw from the final!
- Listen, mother...
I am the Prince and, if I give up
fighting for the victory,
our subjects will laugh at me!
and besides...
- What else is there?
- I want to have proof..
...that Grand Duke Duralumin
intends to kill me.
What are you talking about?
You shouldn't say such a thing.
I wish so much that you would
think only about studying...
...to become a good Prince
and not about fighting!
I love you. What will I
do if you are defeated?
Please, take my advice!
Mother, I promise you that after tomorrow's
contest I will go back to studying.
May God bless you.
- I will return, mother!
- Sapphire!
Lord of heaven, I beg you,
protect her! Make her return!
Now we will form the
pairings for the two semifinals.
The two who draw the
same card will face each other!
- Here is mine!
- Fine!
Let's see, now, Baron's
This is mine.
- We'll settle this between us, Baron!
- Yeah.
And I'm supposed to face
a boy?!
- Surrender!
- Yes!
I won, Grand Duke!
Damn him!
He made it this time too!
You must declare me the winner!
- I am forced to...
- What are you waiting for?
Damn it, I'll have to do it!
Sapphire has won!
- Now it's our turn, Baron!
- Yeah!
What?
- Referee!
- At your command!
Stop the tournament!
I have to do something!
- Good!
- This is it!
Yes, Grand Duke! Say it again!
Well... The fact is
that Baron and Guillon...
...have already faced each other 7 times
and have always ended in a draw.
- Can I have some more?
- Yes, here!
Go on, continue!
This time too
they won't be able to best each other!
- This is serious.
- Only this time...
...they will fight to the death
and they will both die!
First, the old man said
that each of those two...
...has developed
his own secret weapon.
This means there won't be
anyone who can kill the Prince...
...if both of them die!
- You are right, that's how it is.
So first we will have to
kill one of them.
Guillon hasn't arrived yet.
The competition is almost about to start.
The Grand Duke asked me
to come down here.
Who knows why he wants
to meet me in the dungeons...!
I get it: they want to
stop me from winning!
You're finished, Guillon!
Damn it!
I will sell my life dearly!
You may eliminate me,
but I will kill many of you!
You have proven you are
worth as much as the strongest.
There is no need
for you to fight anymore!
Now I can no longer back
down! I would lose face!
- Scoundrels!
- You're finished!
You are finished!
Damned bandits!
You'll see who Guillon is!
- Forward!
- Ready? Pour!
Oh, no! Not the boiling oil!
Let's run! It burns! Fire!
Help!
He fell into a trap! Who
did such a terrible thing?
You say Guillon has fled?
Yes! Probably he must
have been afraid of you!
Impossible!
I know Guillon well!
He is not a coward! He is brave!
And yet we cannot find him
anywhere.
That means you will fight in
the final match against the Prince.
I am very perplexed.
The Grand Duke will give you twenty
times more than what he promised you!
Baron, did you have
Guillon killed?
No, but I could kill you!
You are unfair to attack me
like this! I am not ready yet!
- Let the final begin!
- The final already?
- How come?
- Guillon has disappeared.
Come on, Opal!
- Guillon has been killed!
- What do you mean he's been killed?
You set a trap for him,
didn't you?
Don't be foolish!
I would never do such a thing!
Let's hope they don't discover
the truth!
I know you were afraid of Guillon!
- He feared me too!
- You are a miserable individual:
having an opponent attacked
in the castle dungeons...!
A trap in the dungeons?
Now I understand everything!
The Baron and the Grand Duke
eliminated Guillon...
...so that I would kill the Prince!
Prepare for my attack!
- The boy is not bad!
- It's over for Sapphire!
Come on, kill him! Come on!
Damn it, it went wrong!
Thank goodness, it's over!
You deserved defeat, Baron,
because you are nothing but a schemer.
I only want to tell you one thing,
Prince:
You are an idiot! It wasn't me
who killed Guillon!
What?!
Around you live people
who try by every means...
...to snatch your throne
and your life!
But then, if it wasn't you,
who was it?
Know that when I realized
who had killed Guillon,
- I pretended to lose the race!
- You could have beaten me?!
- No one has succeeded! - You have
too high an opinion of yourself.
Did they say that I am presumptuous?!
Damn it!
Baron, we will meet again!
Halt!
Baron Nylon wants to speak with you
Baron, you let yourself be beaten
despite your promise!
- Give me my money back! - I
have no use for your money!
And now I will kill you
to avenge Guillon!
Damn you!
And you, henchmen, step up!
Forward! Forward! Kill him!
There he is!
It's the Prince!
Good!
I was certain you would return!
I can't stomach
that you let yourself be beaten.
I challenge you once more
to single combat!
It will be enough for you!
Why don't you draw your sword?
Let's begin!
Are you satisfied? If instead of
a stick I had had a sword,
I could have cut off your head
I am a professional, Prince.
Practice and become stronger,
otherwise you will lose your life.
You are strong and brave
for being only a boy,
but to defeat
the scoundrels of this kingdom
...you will have to become
even more skilled.
Farewell!
I will remember this lesson.
Thank you, Knight Baron.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP